# SACHIN KUMAR YADAV

North Delhi, Delhi, India



in linkedin.com/in/sachin-kumar-y-a65a23143



nsityadav91@gmail.com

**%**9315966722

## Summary

Research Technologist Data Science | Artificial Intelligence | Industrial IOT

#### **Skills**

Discipline	Skills Set				
Programming	С	C++	SQL	Python	R
Languages					
Technologies	Industry 4.0	CCNA	IOT	Data Science	Artificial Intelligence
Software/Tools	ADS	PSpice	MATLAB	LabView	CAD
	Cisco Packet Tracer	IBM Cognos	IBM Watson	Xlinx	SAP ERP 3.0
	Tableau	Microsoft Excel	Skill India Portal	ASEEM Portal	

### **Experience**

## Standards & Quality Assurance Executive

IASC Sector Skill Council (SSC)

Dec 2019 - June 2020

- 1) Develop National Occupation Standards & Qualification Packs (Skill development Courses)
- 2) Catalyzing skilling initiative by designing the instruction material and learning resources.
- 3) Use Skill India portal to automate the Skill Development Courses.
- 4) Use Data Analytics tools to predict the Implementation Strategy for various Skill Development Courses.
- 5) Use ASEEM Portal to employ different Artificial Intelligence Techniques for mapping skilled workforce

#### Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology, Delhi

Research Scholar, RF ELECTRONICS

2016 - 2018

- 1) Design of microwave filters
- 2) Design of Power Amplifiers (Schematics and Layout), operating at 30 Ghz using Advanced Design Software
- 3) Design of 4-bit ADC

## Deputy Manager-Instrumentation

Indraprastha Gas Limited

Aug 2014 - Jul 2016 (2 years)

- 1) Prepared monthly report of Compressed natural gas and spares consumption to do future planning.
- 2) Use SAP ERP 3.0 for bringing the spares required to carry out maintenance and to analyses spares inventory.
- 3) Visualized past sales data of Natural Gas Consumption using Tableau to determine the key improvement areas to beef up the sale of Natural Gas.
- 4) Use Excel Statistics to forecast the requirement of spare consumptions.

#### **Education**



#### Netaji Subhas Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Instrumentation and control Engineering 2010 - 2014

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



in Learning Data Analytics - LinkedIn



in Data Fluency: Exploring and Describing Data - LinkedIn



Excel Statistics Essential Training: 1 – LinkedIn



Basic and Advanced Course on PLC AUTOMATION WITH SIEMENS SIMATIC MANAGER ON S7 300 PLC, HMI, WINCC, PROTOOL and WINCC FLEXIBLE - M/S POWERTECH ENGINEERING **SERVICES** 



Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching (CCNA) - CMC LTD

## **Accomplishments**

#### **Honor & Award**



Scholarships for Academic Excellence - Netaji Subhas Institute of Technology

## **Project**

#### **DESIGN OF NEURAL NETWORK IN VLSI ARCHITECTURE**

The objective of this project is to design Low Power Neural Network Architecture in Analog VLSI.The network designed is adopted to verify the Analog and Digital Applications of Neural Network. The network realizes its functionality for the trained targets using the Error Back Propagation Algorithm. High grade performance is achieved by replacing the conventional MOS transistors with Low voltage cascode current mirror and FGMOS

#### **Publication**

International Conference on Signal Processing and Integrated Networks

#### 3D Smith-Chart Applications for Passive negative resistance in RF and microwave circuits

Author(s)

Sachin K. Yadav, Urvashi Singh, Mohammad S. Hashmi.

27/09/2018

IEEE/pp. 788-791

This paper presents a holistic view to represent the admittance in active and passive RF microwave circuits on 3D Smith chart. Furthermore, it also provides simple mechanism to transform source and load impedance using transmission lines on the 3D Smith chart. Finally, an elaborative procedure for all configuration of L Type impedance matching networks using 3D Smith chart is also presented. All the features have been presented through the 3 D Smith chart developed using an alternative approach that utilizes Moebius inversive transformation and Reimann Sphere concepts